Register of the George Koudinoff (Georgii Vassil'evich Kudinov) Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
George Koudinoff (Georgii Vassil'evich Kudinov) papers
1917-1969
2001C29
Hoover Institution Archives
2 microfilm reels (0.3 linear feet)
Clippings, programs, letters, and photographs, relating to Russian opera.
Koudinoff, George, d. 1969
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biographical Note
? Born, Russia
1923 Studied singing in Harbin
1931(?)-1948 Baritone, the Russian Light Opera Company, the Russian Opera Comique, Shanghai Opera House and Obshchedostupnii Teatr pod upr. V. Klarina in Shanghai, China
1948 Moved to the United States
1948-1950(?) Soloist, Jaroff Don Cossack Chorus
1969 March 17 Died, San Francisco
Scope and Content Note
George Koudinoff (aka George Koudinov/Kudinoff) was a baritone who performed with the Russian Light Opera Company, the Russian Opera Comique, Shanghai Opera House, and Obshchedostupnii Teatr pod upr. V. Klarina in Shanghai. After moving to the United States in 1948, he was a soloist in the Jaroff Don Cossack Chorus, then he became a waiter in a San Francisco restaurant.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
China.; Opera.; Russia.; Russians--China.; Russians--United States.; United States.
- Biographical File, 1923-1969 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Clippings (including obituaries), letters of thanks, scrapbooks and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1)
  One letter from unidentified correspondent
- Photographs, 1917-1940s (Box 2)
  Album of prints depicting Koudinoff in different opera costumes and his performances. Includes several family prints
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1923-1969 (Box 1)
  - Clippings. (Folder 1: 1)
    Includes obituaries
  - Letters of thanks (Folder 1: 2)
  - Scrapbooks. (Folder 1: 3-4)
    Includes clippings and programs
  - Miscellany (Folder 1: 5)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1948 (Folder 1: 6)
  One letter from an unidentified correspondent
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1917-1940s (Box 2)